ILGWU Joint Board Dress & Waistmakers' Union of Greater New York Managers' Correspondence 5780/047
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Negotiations, 1954-1955 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  Incl. "Summary of Inflation Clause" (1944).
- Negotiations, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 18)
- Negotiations, 1946-1954 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Negotiations, 1946-1954 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Negotiations, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  Nov. 1950-Mar. 1951.
- Negotiations, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  Sept. 1950-Dec. 1950. Incl. memoranda from William Gomberg, Morris Glushien & Dr. Lazare Teper; complaints from Eastern Out-of-Town locals; statistical table re Columbus Day as a holiday; summary," Matters Not Yet Settled."
- Negotiations, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Feb. 1949-Dec. 1950.
- Negotiations, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Negotiations, 1946-1948 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  Incl. general strike flier (Mar. 5, 1947).
- Negotiations, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  Mar. 1947.
- Negotiations, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  Dec. 1946. Stenographic record of Dress Industry Conference.
- Negotiations, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  Announcement of appointment by F.H. LaGuardia (mayor) of Anna Rosenberg as personal observer in negotiations; press release announcing contract calling for "efficient management & industry promotion."
- Negotiations, 1940-1941 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  Oct. 1940-Jan. 1941.
- Negotiations, 1938-1939 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Negotiations. Agreements, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Negotiations. Agreements, 1946-1947 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Negotiations. Associations, 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  I.c.w. United Popular Dress Mfrs. Assoc. & Popular Priced Dress Contractors Assoc.; leaflets & telegrams re conflict bet. the two Associations.
- Negotiations. Basic Facts, 1953-1963 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Negotiations. Cost of Living, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Mar-May 1974.
- Negotiations. Cost of Living, 1942-1943 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Incl. article, "Observations on the Cost of Living Index of the Bureau of Labor Statistics" by Lazare Teper.
- Negotiations. Cutting, Non-Union, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Negotiations. Demands, 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Negotiations. Demands and Proceedings, 1943-1944 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  History & record of negotiations, incl. Directory of Representatives to Industrywide Conference.
- Negotiations. Dress Shipping Clerks Union, Local 60-A, 1954-1958 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Negotiations. Employer Demands, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Negotiations. Floor Work, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Negotiations. Health and Vacation, 1937-1944 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Negotiations. Holiday Pay, 1973-1975 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Negotiations. Holiday Pay, 1958-1963 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Negotiations. Impartial Chairman Decisions, 1961-1963 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Negotiations. Independent Jobbers, 1958-1959 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  Feb. 1958-Jan. 1959.
- Negotiations. Industry Conference, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  Jan. 1961.
- Negotiations. Keyserling Study, 1962-1964 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Negotiations. Pennsylvania, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Negotiations. Pennsylvania, 1956-1958 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  Incl. NLRB hearing & leaflets.
- Negotiations. Pennsylvania Dress Manufacturers Assoc., Inc., 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  May 1950-Aug. 1951.
- Negotiations. Promotion, 1940-1941 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  Incl. JH speech, "A Program for Reconstructing New York's First Industry" & news release.
- Negotiations. Schlesinger and Bloom, 1951-1958 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  Incl. copy of "Promulgation of the Bd. of Stability and Control."
- Negotiations. Shop Chairmen's Meeting, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Negotiations. Wage Increases, 1941-1950 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  Incl. record of hearing before War Labor Board.
- Negotiations. Wage Reopening, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  Chaikin, Sol Greene and David Gingold
- Northeast Department, 1955-1966 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  Incl. copies of proclamation by local mayors in honor of "ILGWU Union Label Day" (1960).
- Northeast Dept., 1961-1964 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Northeast Dept., 1957-1960 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Northeast Dept., 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Northeast Dept., 1956-1957 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  Incl. minutes of managers' conference; minutes of conference bet. Jt. Bd. & Northeast Dept.; list of N.E. Penna. contractors.
- Northeast Dept., 1951-1955 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Northeast Dept., 1944-1950 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  Incl. correspondence. & agreements with Penna. Dress Mfrs. Assoc., Inc.
- Northeast Dept., 1940-1950 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  Incl. pamphlets of Southern New England District.
- Northeast Dept., Pennsylvania, 1952-1957 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  Incl. leaflet, "It Settles Nothing!" of Penna. Garment Mfrs. Assoc.
- Northeast Dept., Staff Training Conference, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  Mar. 1966.
- Northeast Dept., Staff Training Conference, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  Feb. 1964.
- Office Employees International Union, Local 153, 1936-1956 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  Corres. on contract negotiations for employees of Jt. Bd. & agreements.
- Organization Dept., 1963-1964 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Organization Dept., 1952 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  Incl. non-union firms in jobbers' drive; Itrs. from organizers.
- Organization Dept., 1933-1950 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  Incl. Report of Organization Committee, General Dress Strike (1933) & handwritten outline of account of Chicago strike of 1919.
- Organization Dept., 1948-1949 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  Reports of non-union jobbers' drive; incl. accounts of gangster attacks on pickets & Union officers.
- Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training (ORT), 1958-1965 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- The Organizer, 1933 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  Vol 1. 1, Nos. 1-6.
- Organizing Dept., 1935-1950 (Box 28, Folder 3)
- Out-of-Town Dress Dept., 1945 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  August 1945. Report.
- Out-of-Town Dress Dept., 1945-1956 (Box 28, Folder 5)
- P, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 6a)
- Panel of Americans, 1953-1958 (Box 28, Folder 6b)
- Park-Reservoir Housing Corp, 1956-1959 (Box 28, Folder 7)
- Pennsylvania District, 1952-1955 (Box 28, Folder 8)
- Personnel, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Photographs. (n.d.) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  Incl. photographs of Julius Hochman & GEB.
- Pins and Needles, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 3)
- President's Committee on Government Contracts, 1953-1959 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  Incl. recommendations on scope, methods & procedures.
- Press Releases, 1940-1956 (Box 29, Folder 5)
- Price Range Project, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  Jan. 1952-May 1952. Reports & procedures.
- Price Settlement Dept., 1965 (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Price Settlement Dept., 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  Incl. decision of Impartial Chairman re Jackie Kaye, Inc.
- Price Settlement Dept., 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 9)
- Price Settlement Dept., 1951-1953 (Box 29, Folder 10)
- Price Settlement Dept., 1949-1951 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  Decision by Harry Uviller.
- Price Settlement Dept., 1947-1949 (Box 29, Folder 12)
- Price Settlement Dept., 1940-1946 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Price Settlement Dept., 1934 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- Price Settlement Dept. Agreements, 1923-1946 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  Hearings & decisions re week work and piece work.
- Price Settlement Dept., 1950-1951 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  1951 Negotiations. Dec. 1950. Section work, reports & summaries.
- R, 1962-1966 (Box 30, Folder 5a)
  Incl. ltr. from Eleanor Roosevelt.
- Reports, 1950-1957 (Box 30, Folder 5b)
  Incl. report to conventions.
- Research and Statistical Dept., 1936-1937 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  Weekly summaries of conditions in the dress industry.
- Research and Statistical Dept., 1933-1936 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  Incl. Standard of Living Study and statistical analysis of garment industry of Metropolitan area.
- Retirement Fund, 1964-1973 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  Leaflets, incl. leaflets from Local 1199, Drug and Hospital Union, RWDSU.
- Retirement Fund [folder 1 of 2], 1960-1966 (Box 31, Folder 1a)
  Ltrs. (2) from Jacob Javits (senator); memo from Emil Schlesinger re failure of firms to pay contributions to Fund; merger of fund into ILGWU National Retirement Fund; Rules & Regulations of Fund & proposed amendments; statistical reports.
- Retirement Fund [folder 1 of 2], 1960-1966 (Box 31, Folder 1b)
- Retirement Fund, 1956-1959 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  Incl. correspondence. re individual retirement cases.
- Retirement Fund, 1944-1960 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  Rules & Regulations.
- Retirement Fund, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  Report on registration for pension benefits & report on retirement applications.
- Retirement Fund, 1949-1955 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  Incl. retirement plan for officers of N.Y.C. Jt. Bd. & affiliated locals, minutes of Health & Welfare Council & Retirement Council.
- Retirement Fund, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  Memorandum re Cloak Retirement Fund rules & cost of benefits; statistical report on members' ages.
- Retirement Fund, Reciprocity, 1953-1956 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  Incl. minutes of Health, Welfare & Death Benefit Funds Committee and minutes of local union mgrs. re Reciprocity Retirement Plan.
- Retirement Fund for Officers, 1945-1972 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  I.c.w. Louis Rolnick; "Report of Committee on Retirement Fund for Officers."
- S, 1958 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  Incl. ltrs. from Sumner Slichter & B. M. Selekman.
- Salesmen, Wholesale Dress, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  June 1960. Outline of conditions re organization of salesmen.
- Schlesinger, Emil, 1952-1955 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  Incl. copy of memo re general strike referendum; proposed revision in price settlements & in Health & Welfare & Retirement Funds; ltr. re impact of Taft-Hartley Act upon Health & Welfare Fund.
- Schlesinger, Emil and Abraham, 1940-1950 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  Incl. "Collective Bargaining" by E. Schlesinger & Louis Nizer, April 16, 1945.
- Schlesinger, Emil and Abraham. (n.d.) (Box 32, Folder 7)
  Memorandum, "Breach of Contract - Excuse for Non-Performance."
- Schlesinger and Bloom, 1955-1962 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  Incl. legal decisions and correspondence. w. Sol C. Chaikin.
- Section Work, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  Incl. correspondence., conference reports & memoranda; Know Your Price Settlements (handbook); & statistical tables.
- Section Work, 1948-1951 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  Data on price settlement & section work.
- Section Work, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  Memoranda, "Basic Principles for the Proper Operation of a Section Work Shop," "Summary of Price Settlement Systems in Various Cities."
- Section Piece Work, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  Text of brochure, "Section Piece Work."
- Section Piece Work, 1934-1938 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  Memo of instructions on use of time unit system of piece rate settlement; manual, "Schedule of Piece Work Prices for Cotton Dresses. "
- Severance Benefits Fund [folder 1 of 2], 1961-1966 (Box 33, Folder 1a)
  Annual reports & financial statements.
- Severance Benefits Fund [folder 2 of 2], 1961-1966 (Box 33, Folder 1b)
- Shop Chairmen, 1940-1950 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  Proceedings of Dress Jt. Bd. meeting & JH speech at conference.
- Shop Chairmen. (n.d.) (Box 33, Folder 3)
  Leaflets re strike calls & meetings, incl. Fur Workers Reorganization Committee.
- 60th Birthday Celebration, Julius Hochman, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  Incl. congratulatory ltrs. & telegrams
- Socialist Party, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  Corres. re contributions to Young People's Socialist League.
- Socialist Party, Hillquit Award, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  Jan. 30, 1971. Corres. re dinner in honor of Charles Zimmerman; incl. text of his acceptance speech.
- Socialist Party-Democratic Socialist Federation, U.S.A., 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  I.c.w. Socialist Party U.S.A. & New America.
- Speeches [folder 1 of 2], 1938-1964 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  CSZ speeches.
- Speeches [folder 2 of 2], 1938-1964 (Box 34, Folder 6)
- Speeches, 1957-1958 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  Incl. speeches & outlines by JH & Jack Spitzer.
- Speeches, 1942-1955 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  Speeches & outlines.
- Speeches, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  Radio broadcast, "This is New York," over CBS, Oct. 18, 1948; incl. JH's notes.
- Speeches, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  Incl. speech on Sidney Hillman.
- Speeches, 1936-1952 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  Background material, incl. anecdotes.
- Staff Meetings, 1949-1954 (Box 34, Folder 12)
- Strike Relief Fund, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  Incl. verbatim interviews with ten members re discrepancies in payments of strike fund benefits in Williamsburg office.
- Taft-Hartley Law, 1947-1954 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  Incl. pamphlet. Taft-Hartley Act in Action by Jack Barbash; "Memorandum on Certain Phases of the Taft-Hartley Law" by Emil Schlesinger; announcement of study of employer-employee relations in garment industry by Jt. Comm. on Labor-Management Relations.
- Technical and Control Dept., 1959-1962 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  Incl. memoranda & speech, "Low Wages in New York City" by Mitchell Lokiec.
- Dress Strike, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  articles and clippings
- Textile, Garment and Leather Workers Federation, Int'l, 1964-1972 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  Textile Workers Asian Regional Organization I.c.w. John E. Newton (president) & J. Greenhalgh (general secretary); resignation of CSZ as member of executive committee.
- Training Institute, ILGWU, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  Incl. outlines of graduation exercise speeches (one undated); bio. material on Martin Miller.
- Trips Abroad, 1948-1967 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  Incl. correspondence., reports (some in Yiddish), & article for Forward.
- Trucking, 1939-1949 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  Incl. lists of trucking firms; press release of background material on "trucking evils;" leaflets.
- U, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 5a)
- Union Health Center, 1945-1972 (Box 35, Folder 5b)
- Union Health Center, 1953-1956 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  I.c.w. Leo Price, M.D.; booklets, L. A. Health Center.
- Union Health Center, NYC, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  Report to Health Committee by Dr. Henry B. Makover.
- Union Label, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 3a)
  "The Keys to Selling the Union Label to the American," survey by Louis Harris & Associates; script for Union Label film.
- Union Label, 1958-1959 (Box 36, Folder 3b)
  July 1958-Aug. 1959. Summaries of conferences bet. Union officials, advertising agencies & JH; draft of Union Label program.
- Unions (non-ILGWU), 1946-1955 (Box 36, Folder 3c)
  I.c.w. AFL.
- Unionism and Democracy. (n.d.) (Box 36, Folder 3d)
  Course outline (no author).
- Vacation Benefits, 1947-1956 (Box 36, Folder 3e)
- Vacation and Health Benefits, 1942-1950 (Box 36, Folder 3f)
- W, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 1)
- Wage Increase, Demand for, 1953 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  Incl. correspondence. on negotiations, outline of presentation by JH, news releases & copies of agreement with Affiliated Dress Mfrs., Inc. & United Better Dress Mfrs. Assoc., Inc.
- Wages, Arbitration on, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  Incl. correspondence. & outline of presentation of Union demand for wage increase.
- Week Work [folder 1 of 4], 1962 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  Questionnaires listing week-workers & base salaries by shop.
- Week Work [folder 2 of 4], 1962 (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Week Work [folder 3 of 4], 1962 (Box 37, Folder 6a)
- Week Work [folder 4 of 4], 1962 (Box 37, Folder 6b)
- White House Conference, "To Fulfill These Rights.", 1966 (Box 37, Folder 7a)
  Incl. ltrs. from A. Philip Randolph re Freedom Budget; copy of Speeches from the Conference.
- Why This Strike., 1947 (Box 37, Folder 7b)
  Statistical tables, background material & notes for speech by JH.
- XYZ, 1962-1968 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. YIVO Institute for Jewish Research.